Based on true acts of courage
Lone Survivor is a war, action, drama film directed by Peter Berg.
Four Navy SEALs on a covert mission to neutralize a high-level Taliban operative must make an
impossible moral decision in the mountains of Afghanistan that leads them into an enemy ambush.
As they confront unthinkable odds, the SEALs must find reserves of
strength and resilience to fight to the finish.
Petty Officer First Class Marcus Luttrell, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Lieutenant Michael "Mike" Murphy, played by Taylor Kitsch.
Petty Officer Second Class Danny Dietz, played by Emile Hirsch.
Petty Officer Second Class Matthew "Axe" Axelson, played by Ben Foster.
Lieutenant Commander Erik Kristensen, played by Eric Bana.
Mohammad Gulab, played by Ali Suliman.
Lone Survivor is a 2013 American action war drama film based on the 2007
nonfiction book by Marcus Luttrell with Patrick Robinson.
Set during the war in Afghanistan, it dramatizes the unsuccessful United States Navy SEALs counter-insurgent mission Operation Red Wings, during
which a four-man SEAL reconnaissance and surveillance team was given the task of tracking down the Taliban leader Ahmad Shah.
The film was written and directed by Peter Berg, and stars Mark Wahlberg,
Taylor Kitsch, Emile Hirsch, Ben Foster, and Eric Bana.
Upon first learning of the book in 2007, Berg arranged several
meetings with Luttrell to discuss adapting the book to film.
Universal Pictures acquired the film rights in August 2007,
after bidding against other major studios.
In re-enacting events, Berg drew much of his screenplay from Luttrell's eyewitness accounts
in the book, as well as autopsy and incident reports related to the mission.
After directing Battleship (2012) for Universal,
Berg resumed working on Lone Survivor.
Principal photography began in October 2012 and
concluded in November, after 42 days.
Filming took place on location in New Mexico, using digital cinematography.
Luttrell and several other Navy SEAL veterans acted as technical advisors, while
multiple branches of the United States Armed Forces aided the production.
Two companies, Industrial Light & Magic and Image
Engine, created the visual effects.
Lone Survivor opened in limited release in the United States on December 25,
2013, before opening across North America on January 10, 2014.
The film received positive reviews; critics praised Berg's direction and realism, as well as the acting, story, visuals and
battle sequences, though some criticism was directed at the film's focus on action rather than characterization.
It grossed $154.8 million, of which $125 million was from
North America, against a budget of $40 million.
It was chosen by National Board of Review as one of the top ten films of 2013 and
received two Oscar nominations for Best Sound Editing and Best Sound Mixing.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, fight,
afghanistan, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.